Emanuele Sansone

Email: e.sansone@hotmail.it Website: http://emsansone.github.io/

Summary

A specialised engineer on general artificial intelligence and passionate on problem solving to achieve data efficiency and optimization of current machine learning models. My research focuses on the correlation between causality and unsupervised learning.

Along with artificial intelligence and research, I share a passion for the world of sport. I am an experienced ski instructor with international ski racing background. Since 2007, I've been coaching several local Italian racing ski teams and hold several ski instructor courses. In 2011, I've obtained the diploma of ski master instructor, the highest professional Italian degree in alpine skiing, which allows me to train and coach aspiring future skiing instructors.

Work Professional Experience

2018-to date Research Scientist

Huawei Technologies R&D, London, UK

Working in the area of deep generative models and causal inference.

2018-to date Reviewer

Serving as a reviewer for international journals in the area of machine learning and signal processing, such as IEEE Transactions of Neural Networks and Learning Systems and IEEE Transactions on Image Processing.

Academic Experience

2016 Teaching Assistant, Computer Vision (Code 140266)

M.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering, University of Trento, Italy

Machine Learning for Computer Vision (introduction to statistical learning theory and neural networks).

2015 Teaching Assistant, Multimedia Networking (Code 140151)

M.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering, University of Trento, Italy

Principles of video compression/coding (useful for transmission/storage of video files).

2015-2016 Research Intern

LAMDA group, Nanjing University, China

Advisor: Prof. Zhi-Hua Zhou.

I've studied semi-supervised learning as well as positive unlabeled learning.

Sport Professional Experience

2011-to date Ski master instructor

Italy

Holding several professional education and training courses for ski instructors and candidate ski instructors. This is the highest professional degree in alpine skiing (the total number of ski master instructors in Italy is around 200).

2007-2017 Ski coach

Italy

Coach of young athletes (6-20 years old) in several racing ski teams: Ski Team Sopramonte (2007/2008), Sci Club Padova (2008/2009), Sci Club Panarotta (2009-2011), Ski Team Paganella (2013/2014), Campiglio Ski Team (2016/2017).

2002-2007 Ski athlete

Italy

See a sample list of records.

Education

2013-2018 Ph.D.

ICT doctoral school, University of Trento, Italy

Thesis: "Towards Uncovering the True Use of Unlabeled Data in Machine Learning"

Advisor: Prof. Francesco G.B. De Natale.

Dissertation in multiple areas of machine learning, including semi-supervised, positive unlabeled and unsu-

pervised representation learning.

2011-2012 M.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering

University of Trento, Italy

Thesis: "Multimodal Photo Galleries Synchronization"

Advisor: Prof. Nicola Conci, Giulia Boato. 110/110 summa cum laude | Gpa: 28.82/30

Computer vision application for automatic synchronization of photo galleries from multiple users attending

the same event (C++ language).

2008-2010 B.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering

University of Trento, Italy

Thesis: "Master P-NET protocol implementation on PIC 32 architecture"

Advisor: Prof. Dario Petri, Eng. Michele Corrà.

Programming a master device in a network composed by different sensors and actuators. Implementation of

P-NET protocol over a PIC 32 microcontroller (C language).

Awards and Certificates

2016 Academic hardware grant award

Hong Kong, China

Provision of a NVIDIA Titan X GPU Organization: NVIDIA corporation

2015 Machine Learning Summer School

Austin, USA

Certificate of attendance

Organization: University of Texas at Austin

2012 Merit award

Trento, Italy

Award assigned to distinguished students Organization: University of Trento

2011 Ski master instructor

> Milan, Italy Certificate

Organization: FISI, CoScuMa

2011 Ski coach (3° level)

> Milan, Italy Certificate

Organization: FISI, STF

2007 Ski instructor

> Trento, Italy Certificate

Publications

2019 Coulomb Autoencoders

E. Sansone, H. T. Ali, S. Jiacheng

arXiv pre-print

2018 Towards Uncovering the True Use of Unlabeled Data in Machine Learning

E. Sansone PhD Thesis

2018 Efficient Training for Positive Unlabeled Learning

E. Sansone, F.G.B De Natale, Z.H. Zhou

IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI)

2017 Training Feedforward Neural Networks with Standard Logistic Activations is Feasible

E. Sansone, F.G.B. De Natale

arXiv pre-print

2017 Automatic Synchronization of Multi-User Photo Galleries

E. Sansone, K. Apostolidis, N. Conci, G. Boato, V. Mezaris, F.G.B. De Natale

IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (TMM)

2016 Classtering: Joint Classification and Clustering with Mixture of Factor Analysers

E. Sansone, A. Passerini, F.G.B. De Natale European Conference on Artificial Intelligence (ECAI)

2014 Synchronizing Multi-User Photo Galleries with MRF

E. Sansone, G. Boato, MS. Dao

MediaEval Workshop

2013 Event Clustering and Classification from Social Media: Watershed-based and Kernel

Methods

TV. Nguyen, MS. Dao, R. Mattivi, E. Sansone, F.G.B. De Natale, G. Boato

MediaEval Workshop

Languages

Italian:MothertongueEnglish:Fluent (C2)German:Fluent (B2)

Interests

Volunteering From 2012 to 2014, I've participated to a no-profit association, GiPro, composed by young representatives

of different sectors (e.g. ski instructors, engineers, lawyers, psychologists). The goal of the association is to promote the professional categories on the territory and stimulate the inter-professional collaboration of young

people.

Others I like playing soccer, alpine excursions.

References

UPON REQUEST